Guide to the Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IX: Productions
  - Subseries IX.31: The War Song
    - Correspondence -- Background: "Private Jones," one act play by E. Richard Schayer -- Scripts: -- --Script A (2 copies, both incomplete, 1 annotated) -- --Script B (incomplete) -- --Script C (2 copies, both incomplete) -- Legal--contracts -- Financial--misc. -- Playbills -- Clippings (Box 78)
  - Subseries IX.32: Weekend at the Waldorf
    - Correspondence -- Background--timeline, historical information about the Ritz and the Waldorf) -- Worksheets -- Script (2 copies) -- Photo--Sam and Bella in front of curtain with woman -- Clippings (Box 79)
  - Subseries IX.33: White Girl
    - Correspondence -- Scripts: -- --Script A (3 copies, 2 annotated) -- --Script B; Script C -- Legal--contract (Box 80)
  - Subseries IX.24: Woman Bites Dog
    - Correspondence -- Scripts: -- --Script A (2 copies) -- --Script B -- --Script C (2 copies, 1 annotated) -- --Script D (annotated) -- --Script E (annotated) -- --Script F (2 copies) -- Legal--contracts -- Financial--closing statement -- Playbills -- Clippings -- Other: Bella's response to WBD criticism--annotated manuscript -- Printed Material: Script in book form (2 copies) (Box 81)
  - Subseries IX.35: Miscellaneous Spewack Productions
    - At Rise by Bella. Worksheets, Script (2 copies) -- Big Boy by Bella and Sam. Summary -- Black Stemmed Cherries by Bella. Synopsis of play by Hunyady -- Borrowed Love by Bella Cohen and Sam. Summary (2 copies) -- Can Can by ? Involves Cole Porter. Correspondence, Legal--contracts -- Cat and the Fiddle Clipping -- A Comedy with Music by Bella and Sam. Summary (2 copies) -- An English Play Worksheets -- Gambling by Sam and George M. Cohan Correspondence, Script (annotated), Legal--transcription of examinations before trial -- The Gay Bride Photo with Bella's note on back (Box 82)
    - A Gentleman's Gentleman by Bella and Sam. Script (2 copies) -- A Kiss for Tomorrow by Bella and Sam. Correspondence, Script (2 copies) -- Life with the Wooleys by Bella. Involves Billie Burke. Correspondence, Worksheets, Script (2 copies) -- The Lost Soldier by Bella Cohen and Sam. Summary (version A 2 copies, version B 2 copies) -- Meet the Wife by Bella. Adapted from play by Lynn Starling. -- Nize Baby by Bella and Milt Gross. Script, Clipping -- The Play's the Thing by Bella and Sam. Script (film, 2 copies) -- Sister Carrie by Bella and Sam. Correspondence, Background, Script (film) -- Sisters by Bella (and maybe Sam) Summary (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- Skipper by ? Summary (incomplete) (Box 83)
    - Sky Trapped by ? Script (annotated) -- Spring Song by Bella. Seems unrelated to more famous play. Summary (version A 2 copies, version B 2 copies) -- Theodora by ? Script -- Vogues by ? Correspondence, Clippings -- Unmarried Father by Bella. Summary (2 copies) -- You're Only Young Twice by Bella and Sam. Summary (3 copies, 1 annotated), Script (2 copies) -- Untitled works: -- -- #1: worksheets for play in postwar Germany -- --#2: correspondence, background on Anton Dvorak -- --#3: "#59" Summary--WWII propaganda -- --#4: comedy for Cary Grant and Irene Dunne, by Bella and Leo McCary. Summary (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- Misc. notes and worksheets--some notebooks of shorthand (2 folders) -- Misc. lists of plays -- Misc. clippings re. more than one play (Box 84)
  - Subseries IX.36: Miscellaneous Non-Spewack Productions
    - Anne Frank Correspondence -- The Best Butter Correspondence, Legal--contract -- A Death of No Importance (Une Mort Sans Importance) by Yvan Noe. Correspondence, Translation, Printed French Script -- The Fabrizzi System by Albert Husson. Correspondence, Translation (version A, version B 2 copies), Printed French Script -- Ghost Goes West by Arthur Loew. Correspondence, Background, Summary (2 copies) -- Les Girls Correspondence, Legal--contract -- Les Hussards by P. A. Breal. Translation, Printed French Script (Box 85)
    - The Immortal Idler by Bruno Frank. Translation by Jerome Lachenbruch -- An Old Wive's Tale by Arnold Bennett. Correspondence -- Reunion in Vienna by Robert E. Sherwood. Correspondence, Script -- Send Me No Flowers by ? Notes, Clippings -- The Torch Bearers by George Kelly. Script -- Misc. playbills (Box 86)
- Series X: Short Stories and Articles
  - Subseries X.1: Bella
    - "Arms and the Man" incomplete MS -- "Bennie, My Boy!" MS (2 copies), printed -- "Bennie's Annie" MS -- "[Russian] Bernhardt of the Ballet" MS, printed -- "The Big Chance" MS (2 copies) -- "Big Town Love" MS (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- "The Binding LIne" MS (2 copies), printed -- "Birds of a Feather" MS (version A, 3 copies, 1 annotated; version B, 3 copies, 1 annotated; financial) -- "Children of the Asphalt" MS, printed -- "Cigarette Money" or "Cigarette Over Europe" MS, printed -- "Cinderella on Grand Street" MS (2 copies) -- "City Girl" MS (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- "The Conspiracy on Wheels" MS -- "The Cutter's Saturday Night" MS -- "Deena's Diary" MS, printed -- de la Falaise stories (ghosted): -- --Correspondence -- --"Antiques" MS -- --"Paris Luck" MS -- --"The Paris Divorce" printed -- --"Glorifying the Gigolo" MS -- "The Divorce" MS (2 copies) -- "Down Czechoslovakia Way" MS -- "Fantasies from the Ghetto": -- --Part 1: "Roaches are Golden" MS (2 copies) -- --Part 2: ? (missing) -- --Part 3: "The Magic Mint Mitten" printed -- --Part 4: "The Icicle that Wept Alone" MS (2 copies), printed -- --Part 5: "The Mustard Millennium of Hester Street" MS (2 copies), printed -- "Figure Fragment" or "We'll Do the Rest" MS (3 versions) -- "For Certain Temperaments, I Recommend Trial Marriage" (ghosted) MS -- "Furniture of the Fourth Dimension" printed (2 copies) (Box 87)
    - "Gramercy!" MS (2 copies) -- "The Guy from Heaven" MS, printed -- "Half a Dream" MS (version A, 2 copies, 1 annotated; version B, 2 copies, printed, 2 copies) -- "Hands: A Few Sketches from Life" MS (2 copies), printed -- "The Homerun of the Prodigal" MS (2 copies) -- "The House": -- --"Lilly" MS (5 copies, 2 in German) -- --"Feinstein" MS (4 copies, 2 in German) -- --"The Bad Woman" MS (2 copies) -- "I Know Nothing of the Einstein Theory" Correspondence, Background, MS -- "I'm Thinking of My Darling" MS -- "The Ink-Slingers Debacle" printed -- "The Iron Horse" MS (2 copies), printed -- "The Kesslers" MS -- "Kitty" or "Cherry Flats Fairy Tale" MS (version A, 2 copies; version B; version C) -- "The Laugh" Correspondence, MS (4 copies, 2 in German), printed -- "The Little Lame Chorus Girl" MS (versions A-C) -- "The Last Walk" MS (annotated) -- "Love Pays to Advertise" MS -- "Love Story" Correspondence, MS (2 copies), financial -- "The Lyric Daughter of the Sober Russians" printed (Box 88)
    - "Madame Holzappel" MS, printed -- "Molly Delaney Finds" MS (2 copies) -- "Moscow Mosaics" MS's: -- --"The Beggar and the Merchant" -- --"In Memorium" -- --"Moscow in the Moon" -- --"The Old Ballerina" -- --"She Who Laughed Last" -- --"The Ugly Artist" -- --"The Neppa and the Dressmaker" -- "My Advent into Society" MS -- "My Galatea" (ghosted) MS -- "My People": -- --1. "The Unwanted Guest" MS (2 copies) -- --2. "Painted Cages" MS (2 copies), printed -- --3. "The Manicure Set" MS ( 2 copies, printed) -- --4. "The Gods of the Movies" MS (2 copies), printed -- "Naughty Marietta" MS (versions A-B) -- "The Naughty Princess" MS (2 copies) -- "Of Mathilda Thecla Forte" MS -- "Oh, Yes, The Woman Pays!" MS -- "Once there was a Princess" or "The Gay Goddess" MS (2 copies) -- "Our Unoffical Ambassadors" MS -- "Out of the East" or "Leave it to the Lord" MS (version A, 2 copies; version B, 2 copies; printed) -- "Passage to Paris" or "Bird of Paris" or "Via Paradisa" MS -- "The Passing of La Vie Boheme" MS -- "The Passing of the Stranger" MS (2 copies), printed -- "Perel Brandt" MS (3 copies, 1 in German) -- "Plays and Reviews on Berlin's Stage" printed -- "Princesses I Have Educated" (ghosted) MS (2 copies) (Box 89)
    - "The Reincarnation of Rose Pastor Stokes" Background, MS -- "Sara Resnikoff" MS (version A, 2 copies; version B, 2 copies, printed) -- "Silent Lydia, a Tale of the Tenements" MS -- "Streets of Berlin" MS (2 copies, 1 incomplete) -- "Sweet Poppa" MS -- "The Theater and Other Things in Moscow" MS -- "Thieving Youth" MS (2 copies), printed -- "Three American Dollars" MS -- "The Three Who Could Not Speak" MS (2 copies), printed -- "To the Chesterfield Cluett Peabody Cigarette Man" printed -- "Trousers to Match" (seems unrelated to play) MS -- "Truman Pictured as Understudy Who Stepped In and Saved Show" printed (4 copies) -- "Two New Dresses in Two Years" (ghosted) printed -- "Under the Sidewalks of New York" or "The Subway City" MS -- "The Upper Deck Girl" MS -- "Voices of Spring" MS, printed (2 copies), -- "When the Bells Stopped Ringing" MS -- "Where Starving Artists Eat" MS (incomplete) -- "Why I Voted for Hinkety Blink" printed -- "With a Purpose" MS -- "Women of Red Russia" printed -- "Yetta's Fella" or "An Orchard Street Idyll" MS (version A; version B, 2 copies); printed -- "You Look Just Like..." printed -- "You Meet So Many Interesting People" MS (2 copies) (Box 90)
    - List -- Letter to Playboy, printed -- Articles r.e. Germany, esp. Berlin, under name Isabel Spewack, MS's -- Untitled incomplete MS with references to Mrs. Einstein, Princess Eudoxie, "Arms and the Man" -- MS fragments r.e. Russia -- MS fragments r.e. theater and travel -- Housing article--Correspondence, Background, MS, clippings -- Info. r.e. Kreuzer -- Info. r.e. "For the Love O' Lil" -- MS fragments (12 folders) -- Clippings -- Clippings (in German) -- Scrapbook (small) (Box 91:)
    - Special: Long Works [Anastasia Material]: Correspondence (some in German) -- Background information (personal statements) -- MS by Bella (2 copies) -- Financial (cancelled checks) -- Photos and pictures -- Clippings: Article by Bella (Cohen) in NY Times (original and 3 photocopies); Article by Bella (Cohen) in Titbits (original and 2 photocopies); r.e. Film; r.e. Musical; r.e. Play (includes playbill and printed script); r.e. Ballet; Misc. related clippings (Box 92:)
    - Special: Long Works [Streets or Why I Wrote Comedy]: Bella's autobiography--Worksheets (4 folders); Final MS; Photocopy of final MS (Box 93)
    - Special: Long Works [UNRRA Material]: Correspondence -- Reports and other information (2 folders) -- Transcriptions of Bella's radio broadcasts -- Information r.e. Bella's other work with UNRRA -- Financial -- Picture cards -- Bella's i.d.'s and letters of introduction (Box 94:)
    - Photographs (3 folders); Clippings; Pamphlets (Box 95:)
  - Subseries X.2: Sam
    - "Anatomy of Humor" Correspondence, MS (2 copies) -- "Between Raids" printed (2 copies) -- "Boris Buys a Rose" printed (2 copies) -- "Brands Across the Sea" printed -- "Bread and Salt" MS -- "Broadway Revolution" printed 8 part series -- The Busy Busy People (first titled "A Can of Peaches") Correspondence, Clippings (reviews) -- "Bye Bye Blackbird" MS (2 copies) -- "Confession" MS (2 copies) -- "Democracy Marches" transcript of radio discussion -- "Down Memory Lane" MS (refers to "Spring Song") -- "Exiles of the Sky" or "Salvage" Correspondence, MS, printed table of contents from magazine -- "Gentleman Joe" MS (2 copies) -- "The Gift of the Little Gods" MS (annotated) -- "A Grand Dukes's Diary" (translation) MS (3 copies, 2 annotated) -- Great Farces introduction MS (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- "The Gypsy Pilot" MS (4 copies, 2 annotated) -- "Hands Across the Sea" printed (2 copies) -- "Hero" MS (version A 2 copies; version B) -- "The High Sign" MS (2 copies) -- "Home Sweet Home" MS (2 copies, 1 incomplete) (Box 96)
    - "The Last Job" MS -- "Madame Luck" printed -- "Moonbeam" MS, printed -- Murder in the Gilded Cage Correspondence, Legal -- "Nameless Coffee House" MS -- "Nikita" printed (in Swedish) -- "The Philanthropic Urge" MS (version A, version B) -- "Presenting Morris Guest": Correspondence; MS version A; MS version B (2 copies, 1 annotated) -- "The Prisoner's Song" Correspondence, MS (version A 2 copies; version B 2 copies) Financial -- "Quelque Fleurs" MS (3 copies, 1 annotated) -- "Red Russia Revealed" printed (in book form, 2 copies) -- "The Schoolmaster" MS (annotated) -- "Silver Sails" MS -- Skyscraper Murder Financial -- "The Song of Life" MS -- "The Spectators" MS (2 copies, 1 annotated) (Box 97)
    - "This is Russia" Correspondence, MS, Financial -- "Trotsky" MS -- "The Watch on the Hudson" MS (2 copies) -- "Wings and a Woman" MS, Financial, Legal, printed (2 copies) -- "Without Benefit of Cook's" MS (2 copies) -- "Whom Lola Loves" MS -- World at War: Correspondence, notes; Film script (2 photocopies), title list; Press releases and clippings -- Miscellaneous: -- --#1. List -- --#2. Correspondence, story idea -- --#3. Story idea -- --#4. untitled story -- --#5. Editorial MS -- --#6. Untitled MS r.e. Fanny Hurst -- --#7. Clippings (articles by Sam) (Box 98)
  - Subseries X.3: Bella and Sam together
    - Fragments of short stories (all mixed together) (Box 99)
- Series XI: Personal Information
  - Subseries XI.1: Bella (and her family)
    - Biographical information (MS and printed) -- Information r.e. involvement with Campfire Girls (includes photo of Bella with President and Mrs. Harding) -- Information r.e. meeting Thornton Wilder -- Rorschach analysis -- Grade School autograph book -- Diaries 1922-1923 -- High School report cards -- High School diploma -- Passports -- Personal papers -- Awards -- Honorary dinners -- Clippings -- Family: Brother Danny Lang's graduation program; Mother Fanny Lang's will (Box 100)
  - Subseries XI.2: Sam (and his family)
    - Biographical information (MS and printed) -- School notebook -- Grade School diploma -- High School diploma -- Passports -- Personal papers -- Letter r.e. Columbia Journalism award -- Awards -- Honorary events -- Clippings -- Information r.e. health -- Obituaries -- Funeral guest list and memorial service signatures -- Family: -- --Father Noel Spewack's memorandum (handwritten MS) -- --Father's naturalization papers and passport -- --Information r.e. death of mother Sema Spewack (includes Sam's notes for memorial speech) -- --Clipping r.e. parents (Box 101)
- Series XII: Bella and Sam Together
  - Joint biographical information (MS and printed) -- Letter r.e. marriage ceremony -- Power of attorney documents -- Clippings (Box 101)
  - Address books and loose addresses -- Calendars 1948-1959 (Box 102)
  - Calendars, 1960-1976 (Box 103)
- Series XIII: Financial Information
  - Subseries XIII.1: Productions
    - Royalties for productions received, 1930's-1960's, (6 folders, ) (Box 104)
    - Royalties for productions received, 1960's -1970's, (4 folders, ) (Box 105)
  - Subseries XXIII.2: New York Girls' Scholarship Fund
    - Correspondence 1937-1955 and 1971 (24 folders): -- --Letters from recipients after graduation (1942-1943) -- --Letters r.e. Brightside Day Nursery (1946-1948) -- --Letters r.e. Bella's studenthood at Washington Irving, includes 2 creative pieces from that time (1952) -- --Thank-you letters from recipients (1971) -- Information about girls--correspondence, photos, transcripts of meetings--1939-1941 (3 folders) (Box 106)
    - Information about girls--correspondence, photos, transcripts of meetings--1942-1956 (15 folders) -- Information about girls post high school, not dated (Box 107:)
    - Financial information, 1937-1941, (7 folders, ) (Box 108:)
    - Financial information, 1942-1951, (10 folders, ) (Box 109:)
    - Financial information 1952-1955 (5 folders) -- Other--high school graduation programs -- Printed Material: Newspaper clippings from Washington Irving High School and Wadleigh High School; Yearbooks--Central High School 1960 and Washinton Irving High School 1960; Literary Magazines--Washington Irving Sketchbook, Spring 1948; Winter 1949; Spring 1949; Spring 1950; Spring 1951; 1952 (includes pieces by alumni, including one by Bella); 1954 (Box 110:)
  - Subseries XXIII.3: Palestine Endowment Fund (PEF) Sports Club
    - Correspondence, 1938-1975, (22 folders, ) (Box 111)
      [Includes personal correspondence from Esther and Rueven Rubin]
    - Financial information, 1957-1974, (17 folders, ) (Box 112:)
      [Includes receipts, etc. for Cole Porter's contributions]
    - Photos--include some of Bella and Sam in Israel -- Clippings -- Other: Honorary dinner; Spewacks' award; General information; Sports information; Speech transcripts; My Three Angels production--correspondence, playbills; Maps; Press releases on Wheelchair Basketball; Other--letter from tourist dept., gift to Bella (Box 113:)
    - Printed Material: Pamphlets and Booklets (Box 114:)
    - Financial books, 1956-1961, (6 books ) (Box 115)
    - Financial books, 1962-1968, (6 books ) (Box 116)
    - Financial correspondence -- Cancelled checks -- Records and Documents: General; r.e. Dramatist's Play Service stock (Box 117)
  - Subseries XXIII.4: Personal financial information
    - Cancelled checks for family members: Danny Lang (Bella's brother); Fanny Lang (Bella's mother); Noel Spewack (Sam's father) -- Insurance -- Charities -- Lot purchases -- Travel -- Karen Norwood's trust account (2 folders) -- Spewack vs. Bachman ($900.00 settlement--over what?) -- Auto repair (Box 118:)
  - Subseries XXIII.5: Household financial information
    - Farm at New Hope, PA (4 folders) -- Apartment at 930 5th Ave. (2 folders) -- General (Box 119:)
    - Tax records, 1931-1976, (27 folders, ) (Box 120)
- Series XIV: Photographs
  - Subseries XIV.1: Albums
    - Photo Albums, (4 ) (Box 121)
      [Includes fairly good black and white and color photos mostly of Sam and Bella not chronological. Also includes signed photo of Jo Davidson)]
  - Subseries XIV.2: Sam and Bella and family photos
    - Sam alone -- Sam with others -- Bella alone -- Bella with others -- Sam and Bella alone -- Sam and Bella with others -- Norman Klein's photos of Sam (and Bella) -- Album of black and white photos of young Bella -- Sam's family -- Bella's family (Box 122:)
  - Subseries XIV.3: Friends and Acquaintances
    - Trini Barnes family -- Jo Davidson -- Rosemary Harris/John Ehle family -- James/Norwood family -- Mary Lewis -- Cole Porter -- Regina Resnick -- Sylvia Sims -- Stevenson sisters -- Igor Stravinsky -- Julie Wilson -- Misc. labelled photos -- Misc. old black and white photos, unlabelled -- Misc. newer photos, unlabelled -- Farm at New Hope, PA -- Pets -- The Ritz -- "Child Refugee Bill" production -- Misc. theatrical (Box 123:)
  - Subseries XIV.4: Travel
    - Asia; Mexico; Misc. (Box 124)
  - Subseries XIV.5: Non-People
    - Interiors; Exteriors -- Artsy photos by Bella -- Ambulance and Jungle Gym donated by Spewacks -- Photos for an article on art by Bella -- All the negatives
- Series XV: Memorabilia
  - Subseries XV.1: General Memorabilia
    - Happy New Year cards -- Sam's cigarette case, gift from Bella -- Spewack Sports Center: banners, pin, 2 commemorative coins, patch -- Columbia University: alumni sticker, Journalism School 50th Anniversary Award--commemorative coin inscribed to Sam -- Cloth scarf (gift to Bella from "Pat M.") -- Cloth American flag -- Sam's United Airlines 100,000 Mile Club plaque -- Metal beer stein inscribed to "S.S." (Box 125:)
  - Subseries XV.2: Kiss Me Kate Memorabilia
    - Antoinette Perry ("Tony") Award -- Japanese matchbox -- Matted photo of cast -- Lawrence Olivier Award nomination for Musical of the Year--framed certificate (Box 126:)
- Series XVI: Printed Material
  - Subseries XVI.1: Books by Sam
    - Murder in the Gilded Cage: 3 copies in English--1 includes printed bookmark with title and slip of paper with alternate title; 2 copies in Spanish (Asesinada en la Juala de Oro); 1 skinny copy with different chapter titles--first chapter only within -- Busy Busy People--2 copies -- The Best Short Stories of 1926 ed. J. O'Brien--lists 3 titles by Sam in back -- The Best in the World 1921-1928--"Justice by Limelight" short story by Sam p.36 (Box 127)
  - Subseries XVI.2: Books by Bella
    - The Best Short Stories of 1925 ed. J. O'Brien--"The Laugh" short story by Bella Cohen p.81 (Box 127:)
  - Subseries XVI.3: Books with reference to productions
    - Boy Meets Girl: Sixteen Famous American Plays--script p. 533, 3 copies (1 in next box); Twenty Best Plays ed. John Gassner--script p. 371 2 copies (Box 128:)
    - Boy Meets Girl continued: Sixteen Famous American Plays--script p. 533; Great Farces--introduction by Sam p.5, script p.245 2 copies; Hello, Hollywood! by Allen Rivkin and Laura Kerr--mention p.24; World Drama by Allardyce Nicoll--excerpt from script p.845 -- Kiss Me Kate: American Drama since World War II by Gerald Weales--mention p.139; Musical Comedy in America by Cecil Smith--mentions pp. 303,. 320-321, 342. 350; Horizon September 1958--mention p.61 (Box 129:)
    - Kiss Me Kate continued: Ten Great Musicals of the American Theater--script p.213--includes pictures; The Making of the American Theater by Howard Taubman--mentions pp. 267, 269; Complete Book of the American Musical Theater by David Ewen--mention p. 20--also mentions Leave it to Me p.214 -- Leave it to Me: Great Musicals of the American Theater vol. 2 inscribed--script p.1 -- My Three Angels: Twenty Best European Plays on the American Stage--script p.164 (Box 130:)
    - Spring Song: The Best Plays of 1934-1935 by Burns Mantle--cast list and summary p.381 -- Under the Sycamore Tree: Theatre World Annual London--script excerpts and photos p.148; Plays of the Year Vol. 7 (1951-1952)--script p.243 (Box 131:)
  - Subseries XVI.4: Large books with reference to productions
    - Cole by Brendan Gill Kiss Me Kate and Leave it to Me :--song lyrics, photos. Includes photo of Cole and Bella -- Great Stars of the American Stage by Daniel Blum (photos and a brief bio of each actor): Billie Burke in Life with the Wooleys p.66; Victor Moore in Leave it to Me p.68; Mary Boland in Meet the Wife p.76; Francine Larrimore in Spring Song p.82; William Gaxton in Leave it to Me p.101; Mary Martin in Leave it to Me p.123; Alfred Drake in Kiss Me Kate p.131 -- A Pictoral Histoy of the Talkies by Daniel Blum Kiss Me Kate--photos from film p.268 (Box 131:)
  - Subseries XVI.5: Books with reference to the Spewacks
    - The Society of Independent Artists--art pictures. According to note, Bella handled publicity. -- The Autobiography of Lincoln Steffans Incribed by author--Story about Sam as reporter for World pp.809-811 -- A History of the Theatre by Freedly and Reeves--Paragraph about Spewacks p.691 -- The World of Swope Biography of Herbert Swope by E.J. --Kahn. Ref to Bella's series on slum housing, p. 242; Ref to Sam's reporting in the Soviet Union pp.248-252--series "Behind Red Curtains" "may have been the first use of "curtain" in connection with the Soviet Union" -- Weekend at the Waldorf novelization by Charles Lee of screenplay by Spewacks (Box 132:)
  - Subseries XVI.6: Books by Daniel Lang, Bella's half brother
    - The Man in the Thick Lead Suit dedicated to Sam and Bella -- Die Maenner im Bleianzug (German translation of above) -- Early Tales of the Atomic Age includes clipping of review (Box 132)
  - Subseries XVI.7: Books for research for plays and articles
    - For Anastasia article by Bella:: "Anastasia" play by Marcelle Maurette; Anastasia by H. von Rathlef-Keilman; Education of a Princess by Marie, Grand Duchess of Russia; I, Anastasia--autobiography; The Real Romanovs by Gleb Botkin--mentions Bella's article p.259 -- For Mrs. A: Gertrude Lawrence as Mrs. A by Richard Aldrich. 2 editions--1 includes playbill and clipping; A Star Danced by Gertrude Lawrence 2 copies, both inscribed by Fanny Holtzman (Box 133:)